<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bcaa on A Humbly Arrogant Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.humblyarrogant.io/categories/bcaa/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bcaa on A Humbly Arrogant Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Iain Cambridge, all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.humblyarrogant.io/categories/bcaa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick rundown on BCAAs</title>
      <link>http://blog.humblyarrogant.io/post/2014-03-31-quick-rundown-on-bcaas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2014 21:08:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.humblyarrogant.io/post/2014-03-31-quick-rundown-on-bcaas/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been advised to start taking BCAAs, so I decided I should fully understand BCAAs so I could decide if taking them is truly a good idea or not. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading various things all saying various things. So this blog post is to so I take fully process everything and have something to come back to if I ever wonder about them at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-are-bcaas&#34;&gt;What are BCAAs?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BCAAs are Branch Chain Ammio Acids. Ammio acids are part of the muscle protein, BCAAs being one third of your muscle protein. There are three BCAAs Valine, Leucine and Isoleucine which are essential ammio acids which you need and your body can&amp;rsquo;t produce itself. BCAAs alo cause an insulin spike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;pre-training-fasted-in-the-morning&#34;&gt;Pre training - Fasted in the morning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the insulin spike it will cause the metabolism to slow down, which means the metabolism will be slower all day. Which will result in a decrease in fat burning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;after-training&#34;&gt;After training&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems taking leucine after training when training in the mornings while fasted will increase muscle gains.&lt;a href=&#34;#cite-1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Other than that it seems like you&amp;rsquo;ll get the expected gains from protein after a workout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intra-training&#34;&gt;Intra training&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This seems to be the best time to take BCAAs as the insulin spike will help prevent the catabolic effects of weight training. However it&amp;rsquo;s not advised in the Carb Back-loading to use BCAAs if you&amp;rsquo;re training in the morning fasted. Also BCAAs have been shown to give an increase in energy when taken during training in people who are glycogen-depleted.&lt;a href=&#34;#cite-2&#34;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt; Which if you&amp;rsquo;re on an ultra low carb ketogenesis diet you will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems I should take leucine after working out. With I can do using the post workout shake suggested in the Carb Back-loading book. If I was working out in the evening it seems that I should definitely be taking BCAAs intra training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;cite-1&#34; /&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://athlete.io/2883/how-to-use-leucine-with-carb-back-loading-and-carb-nite/&#34;&gt;http://athlete.io/2883/how-to-use-leucine-with-carb-back-loading-and-carb-nite/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;cite-2&#34; /&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21297567&#34;&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/21297567&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>